

Daniel Piechota

(+48) 603 158 850

daniel.pi3chota@gmail.com 🔀

Warsaw, Poland

piechotadaniel.com (#

linkedin.com/in/danielpiechota/



About Me

Experienced balance-focused developer with more then a two years of valuable adventure, driven to explore new horizons in the gaming industry. My work is characterized by a methodical and detail-oriented approach, actively seeking opportunities for continuous improvement.

Interpersonally, I am open-minded, approachable, and value constructive criticism. I approach every project with a blend of passion and responsibility, striving for excellence in all endeavors.

Education

2015-2019 Technical High School for Computer Science in Lubliniec

Skills

- Over 20 years of active gaming experience
- Over 2 years of competing at professional level in Battle Royale genre winning more than \$6.200 and accumulated total of \$10.000 revenue in gaming
- Out of box understanding of game mechanics in terms of reproducing and utilizing in proper environment leading to minmaxing; burden of optimal play
- Practical and theoretical experience in all game genres
- Strong analytical thinking and adaptability, allowing for quick mastery of new gameplay systems, metas and mechanics
- Coming up with suggestions on what to modify or improve in terms of game design, level design and other aspects
- Creating feedback on game difficulty, scaling, progression and the end game
- Trouble-free adaptation to constantly changing ingame environments, characters and weapons meta
- Fast, self-directed learner with the ability to absorb new responsibilities and expand beyond the original scope of work
- English at proficient level (C1) both spoken and written

Work Experience

03.2023 - Present DevQA Specialist



- Responsibility of balancing gameplay abilities from early stage debugging to requesting missing balance levers and supporting features within delivery phases
- Designed and maintained longevity matrices to guide balance and retention across the game lifecycle
- Approached game design holistically, ensuring all systems supported long-term player engagement and cohesion
- Maintained close communication with developers and production to ensure consistent information flow
- Created detailed test plans for progression-related features to ensure stability of implemented systems
- Oversaw the quality of work within Game Design/Balance teams; tracked live features and internal requests, and escalated blockers when necessary
- Acted as a proactive communicator and problemsolver across disciplines, contributing not just feedback but systemic solutions
- Audited progression systems for completeness and functionality; reporting bugs and raising potential red flags or designs oversights
- Deep understanding and knowledge of progression systems, game mechanics, tools and their functionality
- Experience in the VS to Alpha stage development of a project, their phases and its life cycle
- As part of development plan I delivered endless runner game project

05.2022 - 03.2023 Junior Balance Tester



- Co-designing Outriders Worldslayer post-launch balance changes
- Limit testing builds to provide more data for balancing effort
- Reading and putting into practice telemetry data
- Preparing feedback on weapons and gameplay
- Creating R&D documentations of modern techs for future projects
- Approaching game from the end-user perspective

Hobbies

- Video games
- Vast form of physical activities
- Competitive gaming and e-sport
- Cognitive science
- Technological innovations
- Streaming